WILLEM N. ELSDON

■ willelsdon@gmail.com | **** 909-202-3855 | **in** willem-elsdon | **** welsdon | **** Boise, Idaho

Summary: A highly motivated systems engineer with an **active TS/SCI** clearance and over three years of experience in mechanical design, **systems engineering**, and **software quality assurance**. My goal is to join a rewarding and collaborative team where I can implement my diverse set of skills in an industry leading company such as Micron.

Professional Experience

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer II

February 2022 - Present

- IV&T SEIT
- ullet Lead daily Scrums via **Jira** with the IV&T team and brainstorm solutions to story blockers with leadership
- $\bullet \ \ {\rm Create\ new\ feature\ files\ used\ in\ automation,\ leveraging\ \bf Gherkin\ syntax\ and\ \bf Visual\ \bf Studio\ \bf Code\ via\ VDIs}$
- Verify Discrepancy Reports (DR's) from creation to final integration, review pull requests using BitBucket
- Assist coordinating test plans and events for Integrated Master Schedule (IMS) milestones using Jira and Confluence
- Frequently travel to sites to help integrate the FORGE system, requires extensive cross-product collaboration
 Systems Engineering SEIT
- Spearheaded an initiative to overhaul and polish the MBSE model of the FORGE system while adhering to SysML
- Worked with SMEs from all product teams to better structure and organize the model, ensuring a scalable and future proof representation of the system that adheres to **DoDAF** architecture
- Developed scripts (Apache VTL) for use with CAMEO that captures necessary information for customer facing documentation
- Led various customer meetings (Technical Exchange Meetings, **TEMs**), verifying requirements were met and appropriate actions were in place to meet the demands of those slated for completion

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer I IV&T — SEIT

July 2020 - February 2022

- Performed various tests (integration, regression, performance/SOAKs) throughout the system
- Wrote technical documentation (Test Cases, Integration Cases, Test Procedures) for new capabilities added to a legacy program, making sure to adhere to the requirements outlined in **DOORS**
- Participated in customer facing test events for requirement verification (ran, collected, and verified results)
- Brought new and updated documentation through review (review boards & critical review meetings)
- Troubleshot and documented all encountered issues using ClearQuest and root-cause analysis

Western Aircraft — Engineering Intern

OCTOBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

${\bf Avionics} - {\it Mechanical}$

- Utilized Solidworks to design tooling used in the repair and maintenance of private aircraft (Pilatus, Beechcraft, Dassault Falcon)
- Helped engineer solutions for the upgrade and repair of avionics, leveraging ANSI drawings that outlined installation and removal
- Communicated with FAA DER's to validate designs, once validated I worked with A&P mechanics throughout installation
- Took accurate physical measurements of aircraft internals to identify ideal mounting and repair locations
- Created drawings for maintenance tools of private aircraft, once the BOM was complete, obtained quotes from local companies

${\bf Northrop\ Grumman--}\ Composites\ Structure\ Design\ Intern$

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Ducts & Doors — Mechanical

- Collaborated with managerial and engineering staff to determine optimal solutions (using CATIA) to repair composite parts damaged during the manufacturing process for the air inlet ducts of the F-35
- Communicated these repairs directly to Liaison Engineers where they were implemented immediately
- Revised three Material and Process specifications to create a more efficient manufacturing procedure and successfully presented them
- Organized all previous repairs into one catalog, allowing for quicker repair acquisition and less manufacturing downtime

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering — Bachelor of Science

May 2020

Boise State University - Boise, Idaho

GPA: 3.7

Gem Scholarship Recipient, SWE Member, ME Club Treasurer, Concrete Canoe

Air Quality Lab — Research Assistant

- Utilized Excel, interpreted PM2.5 and PM10 data that was gathered during the summer of 2017 within the Treasure Valley
- Data was collected using state-of-the-art MOUDI II devices which helped analyze solutions to minimizing the production of fine particulate matter, and what could be done as a short term solution
- Presented my findings to Boise State engineering faculty where my paper has since been used as a template for future reports

SKILLS

• CameoEA, Solidworks, Linux, Atlassian, Excel, Scrum Master, Technical Writing & Communication, Visual Studio Code, SysML, Adaptability, Customer Interaction, Troubleshooting, Root Cause Analysis, Log analysis, DOORS, MBSE, Quality Assurance